Fernando Felicíssimo

Dublin, Ireland

Contact details: +55 1699221 3264 / ffelicissimo@gmail.com

Linked in

Objective

Infrastructure Analyst / Infrastructure Architect / Devops / Linux System Administrator

Summary

I IT professional with 17 years of experience in various sectors, such as Retail, Healthcare, Media, Internet Service Provider and Telecom, with proven experience in successfully managing all applications and infrastructure solutions, from development solution to architecture and deployment of web applications.

Demonstrated ability to complete cutting-edge projects in time-oriented environments and successfully redesign websites to improve user satisfaction and retention times, optimize navigation and increase the availability of environments.

Technical skills:

- Web services: Jboss, Tomcat, Apache, Nginx, HAPROXY, WebSphere, Node
- Oracle Middleware: WebLogic, Oracle Service Bus and SOA
- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Mongodb, Postgree
- Virtualization: Esx, Esxi, VMware, Vcenter, Oracle VMware
- Microservices: Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher
- · Operating system: Linux systems (Redhat, Oracle, Ubuntu, Centos, Debian)
- Automation and construction: python, vagrant, ansible, maven, continuous integration and continuous delivery (CircleCl), blue green agreements, agile development
- Web applications: Java, NodeJS, PHP

Professional Experience

11/2018 - current

Senior Middleware Support Analyst

Telefonica Vivo - Sao Paulo - BR (Industry: Telecommunications)

Contributing to the company supporting Vivo applications in the most varied technologies and architecture on premise and cloud, also in the management of middleware environments with more than 2000 domains between WebLogic, SOA and OSB the company is in the movement of innovation in cloud and DevOps culture then automations on premise are being implemented I'm contributing to the micro services front (Docker).

04/2018 - 10/2018 IT SPECIALIST

Group São Francisco - Ribeirão Preto - BR (Industry: Health)

Contributes with the company in the areas of innovation and architecture of web applications and administration of Cloud environments (AWS, Oracle Cloud and AZZURE), virtualization implementing new solutions for infrastructure provisioning and deployment automation (vagrant, ansible, python, git) too contributing to the support of all environments on premise, analysis and implementation of new technologies to meet business demands.

 An interesting structuring project that I was able to contribute to the business was the implementation of the TS solution (Terminal Service Microsoft) in a cluster using the remote desktop web access where the TASY application in browser would be available for example Migration Cloud Oracle environment from US to Brazil and recontruction of all environment architecture

07/2011 - 05/2017

Linux Sysadmin / Infrastructure Architect / Devops

Magazine Luiza (LuizaLabs) - São Paulo - BR (Industry: Retail)

I helped transition the company's conventional infrastructure based ITIL on to modernization and digitization of IT processes, working with some public clouding providers (AWS, GCP and AZZURE) and new technologies for Infrastructure as a Code (vagrant, ansible, python, git) using the Lean IT concept with agile model development.

I contributed as a technical leader on 5 major projects:

- Portal Luiza Portal Luiza is an intranet portal for employees that has several tools coupled to one of them and access to salary information.
- Mastersaf NFE v1 generation and sending Electronic Invoice to the Brazilian Government.
- Mastersaf NFE v2 New Architecture and Infrastructure in Middleware.
- Docker implementation of PAAS environment in Docker using Rancher. I created all Docker environment automation using the code repository (GitHub, Bitbucket), continuous integration (CircleCI, Jenkins) and continuous delivery (CircleCI, Jenkins) running both health tests of code and build automation (Maven) in datacenter on premise.
- Kubernetes Implementation of cluster K8s in datacenter on premise.

05/2009 - 06/2011

Linux/Windows Sysadmin

Unimed – São José dos Campos – BR (Industry: Healthcare)

As a technical leader I had 4 major projects, the main benefits for the company were increased security, high availability of products and services online and redundancy of connectivity with its subsidiaries:

- Redundancy of internet services (Edge Firewall (IPTABLES), BGP, NIC BR).
- Redundancy of connectivity of the physical presence points.
- Architecture and implantation SAE (Electronic Authorization System) external medical agreements.
- VPN and DMZ.

Technical Support Analyst

- 2008 2009: Abril Medias Franca BR
- 2000 2004: Francanet Internet Provider Sao Paulo BR

Internship

• 2004 – 2004: CTBC Telecom – São Paulo - BR

Courses and Training

2008 LPI Level I and II Certification preparation course

At 4Linux, São Paulo. Duration: 240 hours.

2011 Basic IPV6

At NIC.BR, São Paulo Duration: 32 hours.

2013 Power VM administration

Conducted in house by HP, Franca

Duration: 40 hours.

2015 Clouding Computing Architect (AWS)

At SOA EXPER, São Paulo Duration: 120 hours. 2016 Docker

At InfoSlack, Virtual training

Duration: 20 hours.

2018 Cloud Solution Architect - Amazon

CloudGuru

Duração: 20 horas

2018 VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage [6.5]

Ka Solution Duração: 40 horas

2019 DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate (DEPC)

CertiProf®

2019 DevOps Fundamentals Ed1

Oracle University Duracao:32 horas

2019 Oracle SOA, Install, Configure, Manager

Oracle University Duracao:32 horas

2019 Oracle Oracle Access Manager (OAM), Install, Configure, Manage

Oracle University Duracao:32 horas

Education

07/2017 to date English as Foreigner Language – (level A1)

ISI, Dublin

2003 – 2005 Bachelor in Telecommunication Technology

University of Franca

Other details

References available upon request.

Visa sponsorship required.